<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Lost Hearts</name>
    <directory>losthearts</directory>
    <id>2589542827</id>
    <description>The Lost doesn't have health, but he can't do anything with hearts like the Keeper can. This mod changes that! Now, if you pick up (while not holding Ctrl/ZR):
[LIST]
[*] a black heart - breaking the mantle will give the Necronomicon effect
[*] a golden heart - breaking the mantle will spawn a few pennies and apply Midas's Touch to enemies close by
[*] a rotten heart - clearing rooms or breaking the mantle will spawn blue flies
[*] an eternal heart - breaking the mantle regenerates it instantly
[*] a bone heart - breaking the mantle spawns four bone spur orbitals from the Book of the Dead
[/LIST]
Once broken, the effect goes away until you pick up another heart. Heart effects also override each other - you can only have one at a time. Unless you've picked up Birthright, in which case they stack! The effects will still all go away at once, though.

Additionally, for each soul heart you pick up, the broken mantle will have one more second of invincibility, up to a maximum of four (if you had more than four, they'll roll over to the next break).

You can enable this functionality for Tainted Lost, or even just anyone who has the Holy Mantle, as well as tweak a couple of other things, through [URL=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2487535818]Mod Config Menu[/URL]. Characters other than the Lost / T.Lost need to be holding Ctrl/ZR to add soul hearts to their mantle, rather than just pick up the heart.

This mod was inspired by [URL=https://www.youtube.com/c/Hutts2]Hutts[/URL]; he described on stream a hypothetical mod very similar to this one (itself inspired by stream viewer Nevernamed).

Developer Note: If you want to integrate this with your own Lost-related mod, there is an API, documented in the API.md file.

Upcoming: [URL=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2497320263]Visible Lost Health[/URL] support!</description>
    <version>1.12</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
